viget.com 2019-09-10

# Privacy Policy | Viget

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting any personally identifying information you may share with us at Viget Labs, LLC ("Viget"). Our Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the information you decide to share, and help you make informed decisions when providing personally identifying information as a visitor or registered user at our website accessible at viget.com and other Viget-branded websites and domains that point to this Privacy Policy (collectively, "Site"), while using our various services, or while accessing or using other Site features such as through email subscriptions to receive news and updates.

By accessing the Site, using our services or Site features, or by providing us with your personally identifying information, you are accepting the practices and policies described in this Privacy Policy. Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time, and any changes will be posted on this page, and if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice. 

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals, including third-party services used by Viget, or third-party websites accessed through the Site. For these third-party websites and services, we encourage you to familiarize yourself with the applicable third-party privacy policies. If Viget makes use of the services of third parties that process your personal data, Viget shall use only processors providing sufficient guarantees to ensure the protection of your rights. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding the Privacy Policy, to update your information maintained by Viget, or to address any other inquiry regarding our privacy practices, please first contact us at [legal@viget.com](mailto:legal@viget.com). 

### Who Is The Controller Of Your Personal Data? 

Viget Labs, LLC (Viget), an organization established under the laws of Virginia, based in (VA 22046) Falls Church, the United States of America. 

### What Information Does Viget Collect? 

**Information you share with us.  **We have access to information that you voluntarily provide us, including via email, while using our Site or services, or other contacts initiated by you, including for example all information you disclose to us when signing up for email newsletters or event registrations, webinars, meetings, or conferences.

Information you share with us may include your personally identifiable information such as name, address, or other contact information, as well as various other information pertaining to your use of our services such as user data obtained through your Site visits. If you choose to register with us to receive email correspondence you are required to enter your email address.

Your personal data is collected and processed with the objective to deliver products, services, and information to you. Without this information, we cannot provide the requested products, services, or information. 

**Information we learn from your use of our Site or services.  **We may use browser session data to store your session data while you browse our site. Like many companies, we monitor the use of our Site and services by collecting information such as browser type, operating system, IP address, and the like. This aggregate information may include various data pertaining to you and your use of our services. This information is used for our not for profit and public benefit purposes, including to improve usability, performance, and effectiveness of the Site, and may be disclosed to third parties as aggregate data without any of your personally identifiable information.

**Cookies, Pixel Tags, and other data identifiers.  **In some instances, we may collect aggregate data through cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, and other anonymous identifiers. We may associate this usage data with personally identifying information. The majority of web browsers accept cookies and similar files, but you can usually change the browser settings to prevent this. However, if you do so, some functionality of our site may be impaired or lost, particularly any site customization features.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites that are outside of our control and not covered by our Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) websites to learn about those websites' policies and practices with respect to your personally identifying information. 

Viget uses cookies on the Site. A cookie is a simple text file that is stored on your computer by a web browser. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that this may affect the functionality of the website. 

The following functional, analytical, and advertising cookies may be placed via the website without your prior consent: 

**Type of Cookie**|  **Purpose**  
---|---  
__atuvc (AddThis)| functional  
__atuvs (AddThis)| functional  
__cfduid (CloudFlare)| functional  
disqusauth (Disqus)| functional  
disqusauths (Disqus)| functional  
sessionid (Disqus)| functional  
csrftoken (Disqus)| functional  
CraftSessionId (Craft)| functional  
_ceg.s (Crazy Egg)| performance  
_ceg.u (Crazy Egg)| performance  
_gat_UA-1980766-6 (Google Analytics)| performance  
_ga (Google Analytics)| performance  
_gid (Google Analytics)| performance  
mus (AddThis)| targeting  
ouid (AddThis)| targeting  
uid (AddThis)| targeting  
uvc (AddThis)| targeting  
__jid (Disqus)| targeting  
disqus_unique (Disqus)| targeting  
bcookie (LinkedIn — third-party)| targeting  
BizoID (LinkedIn — third-party)| targeting  
lang (LinkedIn — third-party)| targeting  
lidc (LinkedIn — third-party)| targeting  
UserMatchHistory (LinkedIn — third-party)| targeting  
act (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
c_user (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
datr (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
fr (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
pl (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
sb (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
spin (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
wd (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
xs (Facebook — third-party)| targeting  
  
More information about cookies can be found on [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).  

### Email Subscriptions

By providing your email address and an authorization, from time to time we may send you email inquiries with news and information about our activities. We use the services provided by Campaign Monitor to provide this service. By subscribing, you have given permission for this processing. You can at any time unsubscribe from the e-mail list by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any of the emails we send, or sending a message to [legal@viget.com](mailto:legal@viget.com) requesting to be unsubscribed. 

### How Does Viget Use This Information? 

We respect your privacy, and value the information you share with us. Viget will not use, process, sell, rent, or share with a third party any personally identifiable information other than as permitted by (i) the Privacy Policy (including for example by using such data in the aggregate), (ii) the relevant laws or regulations, or (iii) specifically requested or authorized by you when accessing or using our software and related services, for example to render or complete the services requested or authorized by you. 

We use the information we collect to provide the service or transaction you requested and, importantly, to maintain and improve the services we provide, including for example by providing you with a better user experience when accessing our Site. We only use or process your information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected or authorized for use.

We may share your personally identifiable information with data processors, vendors, or contractors in order to provide you with a requested service or transaction, such as to provide email newsletters. For example, to provide you with email newsletters we must share your personally identifiable information with our email newsletter service provider as identified above. We also use information collected from cookies and other identifiers to improve your user experience and the quality of our services. 

We may collect and share personally identifiable information when we have a good faith belief that access, use, or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to satisfy any applicable law, rule, regulation, or enforceable governmental or administrative request, enforce our applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations, detect, prevent, or address fraud, security or technical issues, or protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Viget, our users, or the public. 

Our use of information other than for the purpose of completing a requested transaction or service is on an opt-in basis. This means that you will not receive communications from us unless you have given us affirmative permission to receive such communications. Our email communications all include links enabling you to opt out of further email solicitations, or you may contact us with your comments and inquiries at [legal@viget.com](mailto:legal@viget.com). 

### Is My Information Shared With Other Companies? 

We share personally identifiable information with third parties only to the extent necessary to render services you have requested or authorized, for example to trusted business partners who process information on our behalf. 

We may also provide you with access to third-party applications, such as gadgets or extensions, through our website. Any information collected when you enable a third-party application on our site is processed under our Privacy Policy, but any information collected by a third-party application provider is governed by their privacy policies. 

We may also share your personally identifiable information with third parties if we have a good faith belief that access to or use of this information, or the preservation or disclosure of this information, is reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; to enforce our Terms of Service, including for investigation of possible violations; detect, prevent, or otherwise remedy fraud, security threats or breaches, or other technical issues; and to prevent harm to the personal or property rights of Viget, or other third parties, as permitted by applicable laws. 

Viget is neither responsible nor liable for the processing of your personal data by third parties. To the extent that a third party processes your personal data as a data processor of Viget, Viget will conclude a processor agreement with such party that meets the requirements set out in the relevant laws and regulations. We will require that third-party processors agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy, the relevant laws and regulations, and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 

### How Do I Access Or Change My Personal Information? 

To provide our services, we need to store your personal information when accessing or using our services. You can update the personal information for your account by contacting us at [legal@viget.com](mailto:legal@viget.com). 

When updating your personal information, we may ask you to verify your identity before we act on your request and, at our discretion, we may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort or are impractical, or risk the privacy rights of other users. We may not immediately delete copies of your outdated information from our servers and may not remove all outdated information from our backup systems after you delete this information. This residual retention period is necessitated to protect our information servers from accidental or malicious loss of data. 

### Retention Period 

Viget will not store your data any longer than is necessary to achieve the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy or to comply with the relevant laws and regulations. 

### Specific Information For Personal Data Collected From Persons In The European Union 

Viget's services are presumed to be hosted on servers located within the United States. You consent to this storage and processing of your personal information in the United States by accessing or using our services. 

Processing personal data of persons in the European Union will always be carried out in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR, EU Regulation 2016/679). This means that you have several rights as a person in the European Union with regard to the processing of your personal data. The following overview summarizes these rights in general terms. 

**_Access:_** You have the right to request information about your own personal data that is collected and processed by Viget. 

**_Rectification:_** If your own personal data is inaccurate of incomplete, you have the right to request a rectification. 

**_Objection and Erasure:_** You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data and to request for an erasure of your personal data processed by Viget. 

**_Restriction of processing:_** You have the right to request a restriction of the processing of your personal data in the situations regulated by article 18 of the GDPR. For example, if the processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure for legitimate reasons. 

**_Data portability:_** When the processing is carried out by automated means and is based on your consent or based on an agreement, the personal data which you have provided shall be presented to you in a structured, commonly-used and machine-readable format and you have the right to transmit the collected data to another controller.  

**_Withdrawal of consent:_** When you have given consent for the processing of your personal data, you can at any time withdraw your consent.  

For a complete overview, Viget refers to the text of the GDPR. Upon request, Viget will provide you more specific information based on the specific facts of your case.  

All requests can be submitted via [legal@viget.com](mailto:legal@viget.com) and will be taken care of within reasonable time. Your request will be followed up, except when Viget has a legitimate reason not to do so (for example, when the processing is legitimate and/or Viget has a legitimate interest in processing the data, like when the personal data is needed to comply with obligations by contract or law or for a legal action).

You may bring any complaint with respect to our collection or use of your personal information under this Privacy Policy directly to our attention, in which case we will endeavor to respond to your complaint within one month of receipt. This period may be extended by two further months if necessary. If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction through our internal dispute resolution efforts, you may seek independent recourse to investigate and resolve your complaint. You may submit such complaints to your national data protection authority, or to binding arbitration provided through a neutral dispute resolution provider. Viget may refer unresolved privacy complaints to the independent BBB Privacy Shield Program as administered by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. 

### What Are Viget's Information Security & Compliance Practices? 

We store your personal data on a secure cloud server that is shielded from outside access by a firewall. We practice safety procedures intended to ensure, as far as possible, the security and integrity of all our information, including your personally identifying information. However, no system or information can ever be fully protected against every possible hazard. As a result, we cannot assure or warrant the security or privacy of any information you provide to us and, accordingly, you do so at your own risk. 

We also use a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this Privacy Policy and to periodically verify that this policy is accurate, comprehensive for the intended purposes, and prominently displayed for consumer review. We encourage interested persons to share any concerns with us and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding the use or disclosure of your information. If a complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through our internal processes, then we agree to dispute resolution through a third-party resolution provider such as the Council of Better Business Bureaus (BBB), TRUSTe, or Direct Marketing Assoc., that also incorporate the Safe Harbor Framework. 

### COPPA Disclaimer 

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) was created to protect children under the age of thirteen from unsuspecting practices related to collecting, using, or disclosing any information about them. Our services are neither intended nor directed for use by children under the age of thirteen. Viget does not knowingly accept, collect, maintain or use any information from any child under the age of thirteen, and if a child whom Viget knows or suspects to be under the age of thirteen sends personal information to us online, we will only use that information to respond directly to that child, notify the parents, or seek parental consent. 

### Whom Do I Contact With Other Questions? 

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [legal@viget.com](mailto:legal@viget.com)[](mailto:legal@viget.com).  Complaints will be resolved internally in accordance with our complaints procedures. 

This Policy does not supersede the Terms of Use that govern your use of the Site and any conflict between this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use shall be resolved in favor of the Terms of Use.

_This policy was last modified on 10/24/2018_
